Contact

718-213-5127 (Mobile) sabir.ismail@stonybrook.edu

www.linkedin.com/in/sabirismail-83113b20 (LinkedIn) scholar.google.com/citations (Other)

www.sust.edu/d/cse/faculty-profile-detail/50 (Company) github.com/sabir4063 (Portfolio)

Top Skills

Java

С

Python

Publications

A stylometric analysis on Bengali literature for authorship attribution

An experimental study of stylometry in Bangla literature

Developing an automated Bangla parts of speech tagged dictionary

Distributed memory caching for the fail safe computation to improve the Grid performance

A corpus based unsupervised Bangla word stemming using N-gram language model

Sabir Ismail

Actively looking for Full Time opportunities from June 2019 | MS in CS at Stony Brook University

Stony Brook, New York

Summary

Graduate(MS) student with 8+ years of diverse work experiences, including Software Development, Research, and Teaching in different professional and cultural contexts. Skilled in Python, Java, C#, C, C++, and Matlab. As well as skilled in Machine Learning, Data Science & Natural Language Processing.

Experience

Stony Brook University
Research Assistant
January 2018 - January 2019 (1 year 1 month)
Greater New York City Area

Natural Language Processing and Text Mining: I analyze the posts form the online forums, used by the screen-reader user community and identified the issues and problems regarding the use of the different software.

Shahjalal University of Science and Technology Assistant Professor August 2013 - August 2017 (4 years 1 month) Sylhet, Bangladesh

Course Instructor: Machine Learning, Bio-informatics Computing, Algorithm Design and Analysis, Data Structures, Structured Programming.

SUST Natural Language Processing (NLP) Research Group: I conduct research along with students on Bengali language processing on various topics including stemming, part-of-speech tagging, anaphora resolution, stylometric analysis, automated question answering system. As an outcome of these researches, I have 16 conference and 4 journal papers.

Admission Test Automation: I have worked in the automation of the

undergraduate admission test processing system in SUST, which contain the implementation of the full admission process, start from the submitting the application, result processing and end up with the admitting of the students. Center for research, testing and consultancy (CRTC) SUST: As a member of CRTC, I lead a team to design and develop an online platform

(www.konnect.edu.bd) for the school students to engage in different educational and creative activity.

Medical College Admission Test Result Processing System: I have to lead a team to implement the result processing system of centralized admission test for the all the medical college in Bangladesh.

Metropolitan University, Sylhet, Bangladesh Assistant Professor October 2010 - August 2013 (2 years 11 months) Sylhet, Bangladesh

Course Instructor: Machine Learning, Object Oriented Programming, Algorithm Design and Analysis, Data Structures, Structured Programming, Discrete Mathematics.

Structured Data Systems Limited Software Engineer March 2010 - October 2010 (8 months) Dhaka, Bangladesh

AfriGIS Blackberry Navigator: Implemented real-time navigation system (also simulation) for Blackberry mobile device using Java blackberry native API.

Education

Stony Brook University

Master's degree, Computer Science · (2017 - 2019)

Shahjalal University of Science and Technology
Master's degree, Computer Science and Engineering (2011 - 2012)

Shahjalal University of Science and Technology Bachelor's degree, Computer Science and Engineering · (2005 - 2009)